From the ashes we rose.
We Are Marshall is a drama, history film directed by McG.
When a plane crash claims the lives of members of the Marshall University football team and some of its
fans, the team's new coach and his surviving players try to keep the football program alive.
Jack Lengyel, played by Matthew McConaughey.
Red Dawson, played by Matthew Fox.
Nate Ruffin, played by Anthony Mackie.
President Dedmon, played by David Strathairn.
Paul Griffen, played by Ian McShane.
Annie Cantrell, played by Kate Mara.
We Are Marshall is a 2006 American biographical
sports drama film directed by McG.
It depicts the aftermath of the 1970 plane crash that killed 75 people: 37 players of the Marshall University Thundering Herd
football team, five coaches, two athletic trainers, the athletic director, 25 boosters, and the airplane crew of five.
Matthew McConaughey stars as head coach Jack Lengyel, with Matthew Fox as assistant coach William "Red" Dawson, David
Strathairn as university president Donald Dedmon, and Robert Patrick as ill-fated Marshall head coach Rick Tolley.
Then-governor of Georgia Sonny Perdue has a cameo role as
an East Carolina University football coach.
It was scored by Christophe Beck and written by Jamie Linden.
The film addressed rebuilding the program and the
healing that the community undergoes.
Keith Spears was the Marshall University consultant.
The film explores themes of sports, american football, 1970s, trainer, college.
The tone is emotional.